(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-17T02:32:16.947597",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
3, 2, 1
むかしむかし あるところに ひとりぼっちのメイドがいました。
Once upon a time, in a certain place, there was a lonely maid.
そのメイドは成績が悪く、人と話すことが苦手で、いつもおずむいていました。
The maid had poor grades, struggled to talk with others, and always kept her head down.
周りと馴染むことができなかったメイドは いつしか部屋に引きこもるようになりました。
Unable to fit in with those around her, she eventually became a recluse in her room.
いつものようにネットサーフィンをしていたある日 一つの記事がメイドの目に止まりました。
One day, while browsing the internet as usual, an article caught her eye.
この出会いがメイドの人生を大きく変えたのでした。
This encounter would drastically change the maid's life.
これはひとりぼっちだった引きこもりのメイドが出会った仲間と共に銀河一のアイドルになるお話し。
This is the story of how a lonely, shut-in maid met friends and became the galaxy's number one idol.
今日のおはよう 少しドキドキするな
Today's "Good morning" makes my heart flutter a bit.
選ばれるかって不安になって ああ
I get anxious wondering if I'll be chosen, ah...
だめなところばかりでいやになるな
It frustrates me how I'm full of flaws.
進んでみたってうまくいかないけど
Even when I try moving forward, things don't go well, but...
描いた未来を好きになりたいから
Because I want to love the future I've envisioned.
キラキラッと輝こうか 間違えちゃっても大丈夫
Let's shine brightly, it's okay even if I make a mistake.
できないことできるようになったりねれるよ先は長いから
Being able to do what I couldn't before, the road ahead is long.
疲れちゃったら止まろうか 少し眠ったら元通り
If you get tired, let's stop, sleep a bit, and be back to normal.
したいこと したいようにしなくちゃ あたしじゃないでしょ？
If I don't do what I want, how I want, wouldn't that not be me?
忘れないよこの思いは 重ねてもっと届くように
I won't forget this feeling, layering it so it reaches further.
変えられるんだ変えていくんだ
We can change it, we will change it,
キラキラしたいから
because I want to sparkle.
nanana...
昨日の「おはよう」振り切るこの歳は
Throwing off yesterday's "Good morning" at this age,
なんちゃってだって強くなれたみたい
it seems I've grown stronger, even as a joke.
笑い方もなんだか自然な感じだ
My way of laughing somehow feels natural.
いつも通りはもっと進化していくみたい
Business as usual seems to evolve even further.
怖いよ 小さいけれども痛い
It's scary, small yet painful.
渇いたハート絞り絞ってこう
Let's squeeze out our dry hearts to the last drop.
なりたいあたしが愛でをずるから まだ行けるよ
The me I want to be is yearning for love, so I can still go on.
キラキラっと輝こうか 間違えちゃっても大丈夫
Let's sparkle brightly; it's okay even if we make mistakes.
できないことできるようになるよ 慣れるよ先は長いから
You'll be able to do what you can't now, getting used to it for the long road ahead.
疲れちゃったら止まろうか
If you get tired, let's stop,
少し眠ったら元通り
sleep a bit, and be back to normal.
したいこと したいようにしなくちゃ あたしじゃないでしょ？
If I don't do what I want, how I want, wouldn't that not be me?
忘れないよこの思いは 重ねてもっと届くように
I won't forget this feeling, layering it so it reaches further.
変えられるんだ変えていくんだ
We can change it, we will change it,
キラキラしたいから
because I want to sparkle.
ダメなあたし ずっとずっと歌うよ
Useless me, I'll keep singing on and on.
輝けること 変われちゃうこと
Being able to shine, being able to change,
ダメなあたし ずっとずっと見ていてほしい
useless me, I want you to keep watching me.
（あいわなみゅーじっく！）
(Ai Wana Music!)
月曜日は体が動きません
Mondays, my body won't move at all.
っていうか毎日でした ピリピリ偏頭痛
Well, actually it's every day: throbbing tension headaches.
あたしったら メイドのくせして お料理ダメ 掃除もちょっとあれ
As for me, despite being a maid, I'm bad at cooking and cleaning is a bit...
見てごまいねまいたうん 勝じあるのみです へいゆー
Covering it up day by day, winning is the only way, hey you!
会いたくなってしまったな 今夜も 夜な夜な集まって何する？
I've started wanting to see you tonight too. Gathering night after night, what shall we do?
月火水木金土日 365日
Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun—365 days a year,
画面越しご挨拶 （せーの）
greeting you through the screen. (Ready, set)
「スキだって」言ったって 全然可愛くない
Even if I say "I love you," it's not cute at all.
勝手にヘコんだって 泣いてみたって 全然可愛くない
Even if I get depressed on my own or try crying, it's not cute at all.
キミだって同じ ダメ寄りの人種です そんな優しくして…
You're the same, a hopeless kind of person. Being so gentle to me...
あたしに気があるのかな？
Do you have feelings for me?
もうこんな時間 どんな予感 神ハプニング ああ中毒症状
It's already so late, what kind of premonition? A divine happening, ah, withdrawal symptoms,
依存度マックス メンタル崩壊 あなたのことを
addiction level max, mental breakdown. I want to know more and more
もっともっと知りたい
about you.
水曜日は意識がレボリューション
Wednesdays, my consciousness undergoes a revolution.
っていうか毎日でした ピリピリ偏頭痛
Well, actually it was every day: throbbing tension headaches.
あたしったら 競争社会不適合者 でも挙動は適合者のフリして
As for me, I'm unfit for a competitive society, yet I act like I fit in,
暴言吐いて うーん ヘコんだ これって放送事故？
spitting insults, then sighing and feeling down. Is this a broadcasting mishap?
へいゆー 会いたくなってしまったな 今夜も 自己嫌悪からの脱却
Hey you! I've started wanting to see you tonight too, breaking free from self-loathing.
悪霊退散 成敗だ！ 臨兵闘者なんだっけ？
Evil spirits begone, judgment time! What was the incantation again?
頑張れ私 負けるな！ （せーの）
Do your best, me, don't lose! (Ready, set)
「スキだって」言ったって 全然可愛くない
Even if I say "I love you," it's not cute at all.
勝手にヘコんだって 泣いてみたって 全然可愛くない
Even if I get depressed on my own or try crying, it's not cute at all.
キミだって同じ ダメ寄りの人種です そんな優しくして… あたしに気があるのかな？
You're the same, a hopeless kind of person. Being so gentle to me... Do you have feelings for me?
もうこんな時間 どんな予感 神ハプニング ああ中毒症状
It's already so late, what kind of premonition? A divine happening, ah, withdrawal symptoms,
依存度マックス メンタル崩壊 あなたのことを
addiction level max, mental breakdown. I want to know more and more
もっともっと知りたい
about you.
ああ 特別じゃない 私のこと勘違いして…
Ah, nothing special—misunderstand how I feel about you...
馬鹿ね… なれあいこそが 君と僕を繋ぐ光
How foolish... Familiarity itself is the light connecting you and me.
今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming today!
私が私の事を愛して
I love myself,
何が悪いのか？ 嫉妬でしょうか？
what's wrong with that? Are you jealous?
痛いだとか 変わってるだとか
They say I'm cringey or odd,
届きませんね。そのリプライ
but I'm not listening to those replies.
大好きな洋服 大好きなお化粧で
With my favorite clothes and favorite makeup on,
お決まりのハートツイン巻いて
and my iconic half-twintails curled,
おでかけしよう 日傘持って
I'll go out with my parasol.
ぼっちだって 幸せだもん！
I'm alone, but I'm happy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute,
生れてきちゃってごめん
sorry that I was born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculating,
気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
sorry that you can't ignore me.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute,
努力しちゃっててごめん
sorry for working hard on myself.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious,
女子力高くてごめん
sorry for being a girly girl.
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまぁw
It annoys you, right? You deserve it!
貴女は貴女の事だけどうぞ
You just focus on yourself,
私に干渉しないでください
please don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけれど…
They say birds of a feather flock together...
届きませんね。その陰口
I won't hear your behind-the-back gossip.
重い厚底ブーツ
Heavy platform boots
お気に入りのリュックで
and my favorite backpack,
崩さない前髪 くしでといて
with my bangs fixed, brushed in place,
おでかけしよう 軽い女?ふざけんな
I'll go out. Easy girl? Are you kidding me?
重すぎっつーの！
That's way too heavy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute,
この時代生きててごめん
sorry for living in this era.
Chu! 目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out,
意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
sorry that it catches your attention.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute,
自分磨きしてごめん
sorry for working on myself.
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for acting cutesy,
貶めにしてごめん
sorry for putting you down.
ムカついちゃうでしょ？ざまぁw
It annoys you, right? You deserve it!
手が震えて冷たい
My hands are shaking and cold,
足がすくむ
my legs are trembling.
鼓動が速くなるのを感じる
I feel my heartbeat getting faster.
緊張……はっ……
Nervous... hah...
もう5年もやってるのにな
Even though I've been doing this for 5 years now.
歓声が聞こえる
I can hear the cheers.
熱気が伝わってくる
The excitement is reaching me.
失敗したらどうしよう
What if I fail?
満足してもらえなかったらどうしよう
What if I can't satisfy everyone?
苦しい… 大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's painful... It's okay, it's okay.
いつも通り平常心。
Stay calm just like always.
みんなに届けたい5年分の感謝 伝われ、伝われ…！
I want to reach everyone with 5 years of gratitude. Please reach them...!
ほら行くよ！最高の景色一緒に見に行こう アクタン！
Look, let's go! Let's go see the best scenery together, Akutan!
あっ… うん！
Ah... Yeah!
きょうはもう引き返そうかな
Should I turn back today?
明日はもっといけるかな
Can I go further tomorrow?
きしみ
Creaking...
見つけたい遠く「嬉しい」を多く
Wanting to find something far away, to gather lots of "happy" things
キラリ光るHope
A sparkling hope
動く、動く
Moving, moving,
とりとめないTalk
endless talk
どこまでも続く
continuing on forever.
さようなら孤独
Say goodbye to loneliness.
動く、動く
Moving, moving,
難解なパズルを解くように きっと何回も「知りたい」を知るから
like solving a difficult puzzle, over and over, because I want to know "wanting to know."
だから1・2・3で歩きだせ
So, step out on 1, 2, 3!
今日も明日も昨日も変わらない ならば1・2・3で歩きだせ
Today, tomorrow, yesterday don't change. If so, step out on 1, 2, 3!
回る世界と逆向きで そうさ1・2・3で踊りだせ
Facing backward against the spinning world, start dancing on 1, 2, 3!
今日も明日も昨日も忘れたい ならば1・2・3で動きだせ
Today, tomorrow, yesterday, I want to forget. If so, start moving on 1, 2, 3!
きっとそれが A A A A Answerさ
Surely that is A A A A Answer!
巨大な
A huge
灰色の壁
gray wall...
どうしたいかまだわからないから
I still don't know what I want to do, so
進むことの方が遠く だけどどうか届く
moving forward is further away, but somehow it reaches.
その先がGoal 動く、動く
That ahead is the goal. Moving, moving,
とどのつまりJoke つらきっとコール
after all, it's a joke, a piercing call.
まだ少し行ける
I can still go a little further.
動く、動く
Moving, moving,
暖かいコーヒーすすうように ずっと暖かそれが今示すから
like sipping warm coffee, forever warmth shows that now.
だから1・2・3で笑い出せ
So, start laughing on 1, 2, 3!
今日も明日も昨日も変わらない
Today, tomorrow, yesterday don't change.
だけど1・2・3ではないだせ
But step out on 1, 2, 3!
変わる景色と同じように
Just like the changing scenery,
そうさ1・2・3で踊りだせ
that's right, start dancing on 1, 2, 3!
今日も明日も昨日も忘れたい ならば1・2・3で動きだせ
Today, tomorrow, yesterday, I want to forget. If so, start moving on 1, 2, 3!
きっとそれが A A A A Answerさ
Surely that is A A A A Answer!
深夜24時目覚める世界
A world awakening at midnight,
示しあわせて鳴り出すアラーム
An alarm starts ringing in sync,
妙に冴えた目で察しあった今日のパーティ
Today's party, sensed with sharp eyes,
So lazy busy easy
どなた様もReady now
Everyone, ready now.
難解なパズルを解くように
Like solving a complex puzzle,
何回も知りタイを知るからだから
Because I want to know so many times over,
ワンツースリーで歩き出せ
Step out on one, two, three!
今日も明日も昨日も変わらないならば
If today, tomorrow, and yesterday never change,
ワンツースリーで歩き出せ
Step out on one, two, three!
回る世界と逆向きで
Against the spinning world,
ワンツースリーで踊り出せ
Dance out on one, two, three!
今日も明日も昨日も忘れたいならば
If you want to forget today and yesterday,
ワンツースリーで動き出せ
Move out on one, two, three!
きっとそれがここから求めたAnswer
Surely that's the answer we sought here.
ワンツースリーで動き出せ
Move out on one, two, three!
おかゆ、今日はありがとね！
Okayu, thanks so much today!
いつもさ、ゲストとか呼んでるけど、毎回予定合わせて来てくれて
I always invite guests and stuff, and you always make time to come,
おかゆってば私のこと好きすぎなんじゃって！
you must just love me way too much, huh!
久しぶりにニットのこのセリフ、いつも私から読んじゃってるけどさ
It's been a while with this knit line, I usually read it first, but...
おかゆの方からもそろそろさ、呼んでくれてもいいんだよ？なんて
Isn't it about time you called me out too? You know...
なんてね！
Just kidding!
うんね、おかゆ聞いてる？
Hey, Okayu, are you listening?
おかゆ？
Okayu?
んー？あくあ？なんだって？
Hmm? Aqua? What was that?
聞いてないんかい！
You weren't listening at all!
もういいや、早く行こう！
Whatever, let's go already!
あくあ、おめでとう
Aqua, congratulations.
おかゆ…
Okayu...
我爱你 酔いが覚めない
Wo ai ni, the drunkenness won't wear off,
oh, i need you 恋が醒けない
oh, i need you, love won't fade,
お生憎様の慣れ果て 察して 無問題
A sorry sight at the end, figure it out, no problem,
破滅してみて
try ruining things,
hold me tight トラウマの 味
hold me tight, the taste of trauma,
猛反対 お手 お座りでお仕置き 報酬
Total opposition, give your paw, sit down, punishment reward,
喉の奥が チクン チン
Deep in my throat, a sharp sting,
僕は ドクン ドン
My heart beats heavily,
心拍で孤独 消して みせ てよ
Wipe away my loneliness with your heartbeat,
愛も 恋も 独占 して
Monopolize both love and affection,
僕を 独占 して
monopolize me,
この まま 中毒 に なる まで チュー しよ
Let's kiss until we're addicted just like this,
そして
and then,
get get get on ! get get get on ! get on chu !
get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
熱く とろける くらい に 溢れ た 気持ち が たまらない でしょ
Overflowing emotions so hot they melt you are irresistible, right?
get get get on ! get get get on ! get on chu !
get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
我爱你 無問題 get get get on chu !
Wo ai ni, no problem, get get get on chu!
ポン ・ チー ・ カン 勝負 は いつも トンチンカン
Pon, chi, kan, the match is always nonsense,
僕 に 言わせりゃ チンパンパンパン だ 最後 は ロン でしょ ？
To me it's all gibberish, the finish is ron, right?
もう 何 回 ？ 殺さ れる れ ば いい
How many times more must I be killed?
oh , one night 忘れ られ ない 終われ ない で トキメキ 偏愛 予習
Oh, one night, unforgettable, don't end it yet, preview of fluttering obsessive love,
喉 の 奥 が チクン チン
Deep in my throat, a sharp sting,
心臓 ごと 引きずり 出し て みせ て よ
Pull out my heart along with it and show me,
きもち いい ね 面倒くさい けど やっぱり照れくさい けど 死ぬ まで 忘れられない チュー しよ
It feels good, though it's a hassle, yet still embarrassing, let's kiss unforgettably until we die,
いかれた 街 は ゾンビ で 溢れる 君 は 僕 に 恋し て いる
The crazy town overflows with zombies, you are in love with me,
ときめく 胸 に 繋がる ロープ を 引く な よ
Don't pull the rope connected to my fluttering heart,
いく よ
here we go,
bet bet bet on ! bet bet bet on ! bet on chu !
bet bet bet on! Bet bet bet on! Bet on chu!
本気 で 狂える くらい の 鬱陶し さ が 美しい でしょ
The annoyance to the point of going mad is beautiful, right?
get get get on ! get get get on ! get on chu !
get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
せー の ポン ・ チー ・ カン 終われ ない get get get on chu !
Ready, pon, chi, kan, can't end, get get get on chu!
ほら ね 我爱你 無問題 get get get on chu !
See, wo ai ni, no problem, get get get on chu!
ラブ☆バケーション
Love Vacation!
恋に休み なんてないのよ
There's no break in love!
校則ライン通り越えて
Crossing over school rules,
だってバケーション！
because it's a vacation!
休み明けに なんてね
After the break? Just kidding!
待てないわOh No
I can't wait, oh no!
ライバルたちごめんね
Sorry, my rivals!
小悪魔フェイスでFollow デイビー
Following with a little devil face, hey baby!
ぶっちゃんけ恋とかホントは分かんないし
To be honest, I don't really know about love,
大体アイツもアイツよ！
and honestly, that guy is just...
こっちみなさいよ
Look over here!
大胆不敵な笑みで
With a bold and fearless smile,
ぎゅーっと近づいて
pulling you in tight,
逃げないで！やー！いやいや！
don't run away! No, no, no!
ラブ☆バケーション 恋に休み
Love Vacation, there's no break in love,
なんてないのよ
there's no such thing!
二人だけの特別な
Just the two of us behind a
Keep Out Line！？ Yeah Yeah！！
Keep Out Line!? Yeah, yeah!
ラブ☆バケーション この気持ち
Love Vacation, this feeling
でももう止まらないの
won't stop anymore!
押して引いて泣いちゃって
Pushing, pulling, ending up in tears,
恋のバケーション！
a love vacation!
都合良すぎなんてね
"Too convenient," you say?
譲らないわOh Yes
I won't back down, oh yes!
だってこれは私の
Because this is my
恋だもの勝ったものガチでしょ？
love, and I won fair and square, right?
実際こんなんじゃ足らないし
Actually, this isn't enough,
手繋いだまま抱きしめちゃって…！？
holding hands and hugging...!?
その先はもう分かってるでしょ？
You already know what comes next, right?
やっぱ無理！むりむり！…なんてね♪
No way! Absolutely not! ...Just kidding♪
ねえ、あくあちゃん緊張してんの？
Hey, Aqua-chan, are you nervous?
はきたん、よ、緊張してるよ！
Hakatan, y-yeah, I'm super nervous!
あくあさま、リラックス、リラックス。
Lady Aqua, relax, relax.
ほらあくあ、早く早く手出して！
Hey Aqua, hurry up and give me your hand!
みんな、行くよ！2期生エグゾディア、ファイトー！
Everyone, let's go! 2nd Gen Exodia, fight!
おー！
Oh!
喜びも
Even joy,
even joy,
悲しみも
even sadness,
あなたさえ
you are all...
五等分なんです
divided into five equal parts.
ひとつ 作り笑いも見抜かれ
One: seeing right through my fake smile,
ふたつ あんたなんか大嫌いよ
two: "I totally hate you, you know!"
みっつ まっすぐなこの気持ち気づいて
three: notice this straight-forward feeling,
よっつ 気づくとだんだん
four: before I knew it,
いつつ わかりあえてね
five: we've grown to understand each other.
勉強だけじゃなくて君を知りたいよ
I want to know you, not just study!
大嫌い から
From "I hate you"
大好き へ と
to "I love you,"
変わる 心 についていけないよ
I can't keep up with this changing heart!
どんな こと も あなた さえ 五等分 です
Whatever it is, even you are divided into five!
でも私 私 私
But I, I, I,
私 私 私は
I, I, I'm the one who
あなたが好きよ
loves you!
大嫌いから 大嫌いから
From "I hate you," from "I hate you,"
大好きへと 大好きへと
to "I love you," to "I love you,"
変わる心に付いていけないよ
I can't keep up with this changing heart!
どんなことも どんなことも
Whatever it is, whatever it is,
あなたさえ あなたさえ
even you, even you,
ことも五等分です
divided into five!
少し複雑に心の中
Inside my heart, a bit complicated,
でも変わっていく気持ち
but feelings are changing.
ずっとこんな関係続いたらいいのにな
I hope this kind of relationship lasts forever.
忘れられない思い出も
Unforgettable memories, too—
これから増えるストーリーも
and the stories that will grow from now on—
あなたなしだったら意味がないんだもん
they'd be meaningless without you!
ずっとそばで
Always by my side,
教えてね
teach me, okay?
だけど勝手に
But on my own,
胸の鼓動高鳴る
my heart beats wildly.
運命だって
It's destiny,
信じられる
I can believe in it,
おんなじ気持ちね
sharing the same feeling.
またいつかいつか
Someday, someday,
いつかいつかこの日を
someday we'll dream of this day again.
夢に見るかな
Will we dream of it?
少しずつ変わる想い
Feelings changing little by little,
焦りや苛立ち和らいでく
impatience and irritation melting away.
信じきれる自信
Confidence I can truly believe in,
胸の奥に隠れてる言葉
words hidden deep in my heart.
甘えベタだけどいいんですかねって
"I'm bad at acting spoiled, is that alright?"
私ついていくわ いつまでも
I'll follow you forever!
忘れられない出逢えた奇跡偶然じゃないそうでしょう？
Unforgettable miracle of meeting—it wasn't a coincidence, right?
大嫌いから大嫌いから
From "I hate you," from "I hate you,"
大好きへと大好きへと
to "I love you," to "I love you,"
変わる心に付いていけないよ
I can't keep up with this changing heart!
どんなこともどんなことも
Whatever it is, whatever it is,
あなたさえあなたさえ
even you, even you,
ことも五等分です
divided into five!
でも私私
But me, me,
私私私は
me, me, I'm the one who
ずっとずっとずっと
always, always, always,
ずっとあなたに愛を誓います
always vows my love to you!
we are the brides !
We are the brides!
喜びも
Happiness and...
悲しみも
Sadness and...
あなたさえ 五等分なんです
Even you are divided in five equal parts.
あくたん！あくたん！あくあくあくたん！
Akutan! Akutan! Aku-Aku-Akutan!
ちょっとこの人うるさいんですけど。あくたんじまおっけー？
This person is kind of annoying. Is Akutan Island okay?
ふふっ、二人とも緊張しなさすぎ！
Hehe, you two aren't nervous at all!
よし、行こうか！
Alright, let's go!
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな
I wonder if I became the me I always dreamed of being...
とうに帰れないとこまで来みたい
having come to a place from which I can no longer return.
自分の足で二段飛ばしてそうもっと先へ駆け出していけるはずだから ran away
Running away because I should be able to dash even further ahead by taking two steps at a time on my own feet.
深くなる傷を縫い付け
Stitching up the deepening wounds,
繋ぐパス軸に回り出す
spinning around on the connecting path's axis.
慣れた痛み 焦る呼吸とビート 気付かないふりしてまた一人
Used to the pain, with hurried breath and beats, pretending not to notice as I'm all alone again.
何が正当？ ないない永劫 誰が間違った対価払うの
What is right? There is no eternity. Who pays the wrong price?
あんたが嫌いなあいつはきっと ただ「それだけ」で不正解なんだ
That person you hate so much is surely just "incorrect" for that very reason.
0点だって提言したって全然納得できない理由も
Even if I propose it's zero points, the reason still isn't convincing at all.
最前線はいつだってここだった 最善策は最初からなかった
The front line was always right here. The best solution was never there from the start.
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks down.
ゆりゆり首を締めるように昨日の僕が殺されていく
As if slowly, slowly choking, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れ飽く
Slowly and gently, drifting apart and growing weary.
ぐらりんにきみにきこえるのは僕が知らない声になってく
Swaying, what reaches you turns into a voice I don't know.
幼い頃から 気付いたら傍にいた
Ever since I was young, before I knew it, you were by my side,
まるで空気のようだ 僕は君とぎゅっと手をつないで
just like air. I held your hand tightly,
楽しいことも涙も 僕は君に話して聞かせた
and told you all about my happy moments and tears.
僕を笑う人や蔑む声が聞こえぬように君は歌った
You sang so that the voices of people laughing at or despising me wouldn't reach me.
この声を君が受信 また夜毎投影されてく憂い
You received this voice, and every night sorrows are projected.
使い捨てだっていいって腐っても止まらないハイファイ、サイガイシト
Even if disposable or rotting, the unstoppable hi-fi zeitgeist—
一周巡る間のたった一瞬だけでも交わる鼓動、音、繋ぐ色
Just for a fleeting moment in a full rotation, crossing heartbeats, sounds, connecting colors.
次は僕が君に歌うから
Next time, I will sing for you.
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks down.
ゆりゆり首を締めるように昨日の僕が殺されていく
As if slowly, slowly choking, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れ飽く
Slowly and gently, drifting apart and growing weary.
ぐらりんにきみにきこえるのは僕が知らない声になってく
Swaying, what reaches you turns into a voice I don't know.
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks down.
ゆりゆり首を締めるように昨日の僕が殺されていく
As if slowly, slowly choking, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れ飽く
Slowly and gently, drifting apart and growing weary.
ぐらりんにきみにきこえるのは僕が知らない声になってく
Swaying, what reaches you turns into a voice I don't know.
いつか君に届くかな いやそんな日はきっと来ないだろうな
Will this reach you someday? No, that day will surely never come.
声も体も持たぬ君に救われた数億人の一人
One of the hundreds of millions saved by you, who has no voice or body.
赤青合わせ彩った音で世界が溢れた
The world overflowed with sounds colored in mixed red and blue.
巡り巡り出会ったこの音を聴くすべてが
Everyone who listens to this sound we met through endless cycles...
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks down.
ゆりゆり首を締めるように昨日の僕が殺されていく
As if slowly, slowly choking, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れ飽く
Slowly and gently, drifting apart and growing weary.
ぐらりんにきみにきこえるのは僕が知らない声になってく
Swaying, what reaches you turns into a voice I don't know.
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks down.
ゆりゆり首を締めるように昨日の僕が殺されていく
As if slowly, slowly choking, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れ飽く
Slowly and gently, drifting apart and growing weary.
ぐらりんにきみにきこえるのは僕が知らない声になってく
Swaying, what reaches you turns into a voice I don't know.
社長……ってそっか もう社長じゃないんだ。
"Boss... oh right, you're not the boss anymore."
先に行ってますからね。
"I'll be going on ahead."
もうあくきん遅すぎて、マリンおばあちゃんになっちゃうんだよ！
"Aqua, you're so slow, I'm gonna turn into Granny Marine!"
顔を合わせたら喧嘩してばかり
Whenever we met, we were always fighting,
それもいい思い出だった
Even that was a good memory.
きみが教えてくれたんだもう怖くない
You taught me that, so I'm no longer scared.
どんな不自由でも
No matter how much hardship there is,
幸せは掴める だから
happiness can be grasped, so
ひとりでもゆくよ
I'll go on alone,
例え辛くても
even if it's painful.
きみと見た夢は 必ず持ってくよ
The dream I saw with you, I will definitely carry it with me.
きみとがよかった 他の誰でもない
I'm glad it was you, no one else.
でも目覚めた朝 きみはいないんだね
Yet on the morning I woke up, you weren't there anymore.
ずっと遊んでいれる そんな気がしてた
I felt like we could keep playing forever,
気がしていただけ
I know it was just a feeling,
わかっている
I understand.
生まれてきたこと もう後悔はしない
I have no regrets about being born.
祭りのかみみたい 寂しいけどそろそろ行こう
It's like after a festival, it's lonely, but it's about time to go.
どこまでもゆくよ ここで知ったこと
I'll go anywhere, what I learned here,
幸せという夢を 叶えてみせるよ
I'll make the dream called happiness come true.
きみと離れても どんなに遠くなっても
Even if I'm separated from you, no matter how far away we become,
新しい朝に あたしは生きるよ
I will live in the new morning.
ひとりでもゆくよ 死にたくなっても
I'll go on alone, even if I want to die.
声が聞こえるよ 死んではいけないと
I can hear your voice, saying I must not die.
例え辛くても 寂しさに泣いても
Even if it's painful, even if I cry in loneliness,
心の奥には 温もりを感じるよ
Deep in my heart, I feel warmth.
巡って流れて 時は移ろいだ
Spinning and flowing, time shifted away.
もう何があったか 思い出せないけど
I can't remember what happened anymore, but
目を閉じてみれば 誰かの笑い声
When I close my eyes and look, someone's laughter.
誰かの笑い声
Someone's laughter
なぜかそれがいいの
For some reason, that is good
一番の宝物
My most precious treasure
ひとりでもゆくよ
I will go even if I'm alone,
どこまでもゆくよ
I will go anywhere,
ふたりとも サイコーだったみんな
Both of you... were the best, everyone.
アクキン建設を楽しんでくれた 世界中の人へ
To everyone around the world who enjoyed Akukin Construction,
ありがとう
Thank you.
あくあ先パイ！開けっ放しだよ、ペコよ？
Aqua-senpai! You left the door wide open, peko?
ペコラちゃん…
Pekora-chan...
ごめん…待っててくれてありがとう
I'm sorry... Thank you for waiting for me.
いつもモノクロだった瞳の奥の
In the depths of eyes that were always monochrome,
景色捨てたら夢見つけた
when I threw away the scenery, I found a dream.
何もない世界で創る絆は
The bonds we create in a world with nothing
強い意志与えた
gave us strong wills.
裏返した日常でまた走って行く先に
In everyday life turned inside out, at the place I ran to ahead,
君はいた
you were there.
触れた心は輝いた鮮やかな色になって
The heart I touched shone in brilliant colors,
羽ばたくよ希望乗せて
taking flight with hope on board.
無限に広がる空の下集まった
Gathered under the infinitely expanding sky,
願い守り進めば
if we protect our wishes and move forward,
まだ誰も知らない明日へと
toward a tomorrow no one knows yet.
引き寄せられるように覗いた瞬間
The moment I peeked as if drawn in,
光の糸は君包んだ
the threads of light wrapped around you.
細くちぎれそうな絡まった運命
Fate, tangled and ready to snap,
きっとまだ変われる
can surely still change.
間違えても信じた道は新しい景色を照らすだろう
Even if mistaken, the path we believed in will illuminate new scenery.
巡る時の中で笑って様々な想い持って
Smiling amidst the revolving time, holding various feelings,
始めようまた一から
let's start over from the beginning.
辿り着いた儚い奇跡壊れないように
So that the fleeting miracle we reached won't break,
手を伸ばし繋げば
if we reach out our hands and connect,
ほら君は側でいつまでも
look, you are by my side, forever and ever...
まだ透明な私たちはどんな色にも
We, still transparent, into any color...
流れ行く 時は満ちて
The time has passed and the end has arrived,
溢れ出す 揺れる想い
feelings ripple and overflow.
もしも未来に待つ運命が僅かでも
Even if the future awaiting us is fleeting,
立ち向かえる 信じ合える
we can stand up and trust each other.
変わらないパートナー(きみ)が側にいるから
Because, as always, you are by my side.
走って行く先に 君はいた
At the destination of my run, you were there.
触れた
When we touched,
心は輝いた
our hearts shone bright.
鮮やかな色になって
Into vivid colors,
羽ばたくよ
we will spread our wings.
希望を乗せて
Carrying hope, spreading limitlessly
限りなく広がる空の下 集まった
under the vast sky, our gathered wishes
願い 守り抜けば 君と誓ったあの日の記憶
if protected, will revive the memories of the day we vowed,
今越えて 過去から
now transcending the past
まだ誰も知らない 明日へと
toward a tomorrow no one knows yet.
ずっと一人ぼっちだった。
I was all alone the whole time.
孤独だった。
I was lonely.
寂しかった。
I was sad.
でも今は一人じゃない。大切な仲間たちがいる。
But now I'm not alone. I have precious friends.
応援してくれてるファンのみんながいる。
There are all the fans supporting me.
昔の私…もう大丈夫だよ。
My past self... it's okay now.
私はもう一人じゃない。
I'm no longer alone.
だから…大丈夫！
So... it's going to be alright!
銀河一アイドルみなとあくあ世界中あくあ色に染まれ！
The galaxy's number one idol, Minato Aqua! Paint the whole world Aqua color!
何をしていても不器用で
I'm clumsy in everything I do,
何かとミスばっか
always making mistakes.
ダメダメな私だって できることがあるの
Even as hopeless as I am, there are things I can do.
凹んで悲しかったって 笑顔にしてあげるんだ
When you're down and sad, I'll make you smile.
ここにいるから 早く 私を見つけてね
I'm right here, so hurry up and find me!
いつでも隣にいるし
I'll always be by your side,
いつでも一緒に笑える
and we can always laugh together.
私をたくさん知って たくさん好きって言って
Get to know me well and tell me you love me.
ワガママで朝も苦手
I'm selfish and hate mornings,
ドジだしダメダメだけど
clumsy and hopeless,
それでも私の事を見ててね 描く夢の未来へ続く道程をキミと歩けますように
but still, keep watching over me so we can walk the path to our dream future together.
ねぇ もっと！
Hey, even more!
好きになってもらいたいのだ
I want you to love me even more!
頭の中は君ばっか ってゆうかそっぽ向かないで！
My head is full of you—hey, don't look away!
あぁもう！ ヤキモキしちゃうわ あぁ
Oh geez! It makes me all anxious, ah!
ずっとずっと好きがいいの 心の奥もトキメイちゃうくらいに
I want you to love me forever and ever, enough to make my heart flutter.
こっち向いててねダーリン？ あぁもう離さないから
Look this way, darling? Ah, I'll never let you go,
絶対に！
absolutely!
キミがいるから私
Because you are here,
いつでも頑張れるんだ
I can always do my best.
落ち込んで悲しかったって
Even if I get down and sad,
キミがいるから
because you are here.
みんなのおかげで ここまで来ることができました！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to make it this far!
六年目もみんな あくあ色に染まれー！
In our sixth year too, everyone, get dyed in Aqua color!
君がいるから 歩いて来れた
I could walk this far because you're here,
君がいるから…
because you're here...
前も向けないような 事とか辛いこととかあったって
Even when there were times I couldn't face forward or things were tough,
君の力でここまで笑って来れたんだ
I was able to keep smiling and make it this far with your strength.
君がいるから 私がいるの
You're here, so I'm here.
こんな私を愛してくれるね もっと
You love even someone like me, even more.
ねぇもっと まだもっと 受け止めてよね
Hey, even more, even more, accept it all, okay?
ねぇ さぁ声を上げて
Hey, come on, raise your voice!
ねぇもっと ねぇもっと 好きになってもらいたいと
Hey, even more, even more, I want you to love me more,
いくらでもそう 私ばっかりみたいよ
It's like I'm always the only one.
そっぽなんて抜かせないよ 寝返り夢中にしちゃうわ ああ
I won't let you look away! I'll have you completely hooked in my dreams, ah!
ずっとずっと好きだよ
I'll love you forever and ever.
心も体も染まっちゃうくらいにこっち向いててよねぇダーリン ああもう離さないから
So that my heart and body are completely dyed, look this way, hey darling, ah, I won't let you go anymore!
絶対に 絶対ね 絶対よ 約束だよ
Definitely, absolutely, for sure, it's a promise!
愛しちゃうもっと
I'll love you even more!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ということで、ここまでノンストップでお届けしてきまして
So, we've delivered this nonstop up to this point,
みなとあくあ 5周年ライブ みんなどうだったー！？
Minato Aqua 5th Anniversary Live! How was it, everyone?!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということでね、えー皆様のおかげで、えー無事！ 5周年を迎えることができました！
So, thanks to all of you, we safely reached our 5th anniversary!
みんな本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you all so, so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということでね、えーコメントもたくさん、ありがとーー！ あたふちゅ、ありがとうございます！
So, um, thank you so much for all the comments! Atafuchu, thank you!
最高だった？
Was it the best?
本当に？ ありがとう！
Really? Thank you!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
いや、なんとね、もうここまで、え、ゲストさんもたくさん来てくれて
And you know, we've had so many guests come join us up to this point,
いやあ、どうですか？ エモかったですか？
So, how was it? Was it emotional?
ちょっとね、あの私がみんなに込めた思い、そしてみんなに届けたい気持ちをたくさん、え、込めて作った、え、ライブでございます！ みんな本当にね、見てくれてありがとう！
I put a lot of feelings into this live that I wanted to convey to everyone! Thank you all so much for watching!
なんと！ なんとトレンドが1位になった！ すごい！ ありがとう！
And guess what! Trends reached #1! Amazing! Thank you!
やご水着配信ぶりだ！
It's been since the Yagoo swimsuit stream!
ははは、ありがとう！ 本当にありがとうございます！
Haha, thank you! Thank you so much!
いや、嬉しいです！ いや、ここまでね来られたのも本当にみんなのおかげだと思ってます！
I'm so happy! I truly believe making it this far is thanks to everyone!
6周年もよろしくお願いします！ ありがとうねー！
Please continue to support our 6th year too! Thank you!
あ、まだね、続くからね！ まだ続きますから！
Oh, it's still going, you know! It's still continuing!
そして、なんと今回はですね、私の5周年をお祝いしてメッセージを送ってくださってる方がいらっしゃるみたいなので、いやちょっと私もちょっと中身をまだ見ていなくて、ちょっと楽しみなんだよね！ それじゃあ早速VTRどうぞ！
And what's more, this time, it seems there are people who sent congratulatory messages for my 5th anniversary. I haven't seen the contents yet myself, so I'm really looking forward to it! Now then, without further ado, roll the VTR!
こんにちは、ホロライブスタッフの友人Aです！ あくあさん、5周年おめでとうございます！
Hello, I'm A-chan, Hololive staff! Aqua-san, congratulations on your 5th anniversary!
最初会ってから、もう5周年が、5年が経過していることにちょっとびっくりですけれども
I'm a bit surprised that 5 years have already passed since we first met,
まあ、あくあさんは最初ね、会った時から、ちっちゃいながらもすごく可愛くて、クルーの皆さんや周りのことも思って
Well, Aqua-san, ever since we first met, even though she was tiny, she was so cute, caring about the crew and those around her,
うん、そして歌もダンスも頑張っていて、がんばり屋なアイドルだなっていう印象がとってもあります！ 色々なホロメンもね、あの可愛がってもらっているなというイメージがありますし
Yeah, and working hard at singing and dancing, giving the strong impression of a hardworking idol! I have the impression she's cherished by various Hololive members too,
なんか色んなところも成長、成長を感じる
And I feel growth in various ways...
ゲームもね、めちゃめちゃ上り詰めて頑張るっていうところをね、いつも応援しておりますが
I always cheer on how she climbs up and works hard in games, but
一点、あくあさんを見ていてすごく気づきがあったというか
There's one thing I noticed very strongly while watching Aqua-san...
学びがありました
I've learned a lesson.
なん だろ
I wonder what it is.
あの 色々なところが成長していても 意外とコミュ力って伸びないですねw
Even though various parts of me have grown, my communication skills surprisingly haven't improved lol
それでは
Well then,
また バイバーイ！
see you again, bye-bye!
今度は直接煽らせてくださいな wwww
Next time, let me provoke you directly lol
ははははじゃないよ！ 何何これ？
That's not "haha"! What on earth is this?
なんか 芸能人とかからのさ メッセージかと思った。Aちゃんじゃん！ ありがとうAちゃん！ありがとうございます！
I thought it was a message from some celebrity. It's A-chan! Thanks, A-chan! Thank you so much!
いやー ま 5周年にま ふさわしい ね 相手ではございますけども
Well, she's a fitting opponent for my 5th anniversary, but...
なんか え？ な 何？ Aちゃん なんか嫉妬してんの 私の成長っぷりに 本当にまったく 最近丸くなったAちゃんなんですけども ちょっとなんかじゃん 若干尖ってたな あいつ許せねぇな マジで。
Are you jealous of my growth, A-chan? Seriously, A-chan has become so mellow lately, but she was a bit edgy back then. I can't forgive her, seriously.
え？ なんと もう1人 メッセージをくれた人がいるみたいです。 ちょっと やっぱりこれ Aちゃんはちょっと 全然だったもしれない。いやいやそんなことありがとうございます！
Huh? It seems there's another person who sent a message. Well, maybe A-chan wasn't quite... No, no, thank you so much!
誰だ？ 大物らしいぞ。すごい大物からの メッセージが届いてるみたいです。
Who is it? Sounds like a bigwig. It seems a message from a huge bigwig has arrived.
それでは VTR どうぞ！
Now then, roll the VTR!
カバー株式会社の谷郷元昭です よろしくお願いします
I'm Motoaki Tanigo from Cover Corp. Nice to meet you.
あかさんご 周年 おめでとうございます
Congratulations, Aqua-san, on your 5th anniversary.
5周いって本当に 本当に早いですよね。
5 years is really, truly fast, isn't it?
本当に今まで あの頑張っていただいてありがとうございます
Thank you so much for working hard up until now.
いやこちらこそ ありがとうございます！
No, thank you very much!
なんでこのまま このままなんだよ あかさんとの思い出ですが
Why are you reading straight off the script? Anyway, regarding my memories with Aqua-san...
大本読んでる あかさん あの2期生の中で あの1人単独のオーディションだったの オーディションだったので、あいう方が来るのかなって思ってた中であの覚えていただいてまさにこの人があかさんだなと思ったこと覚えております
Reading the script! Aqua-san was the only one in the 2nd generation who had a solo audition. Since it was an audition, I wondered what kind of person would come, and I remember thinking, "Ah, this is Aqua-san" when I met you.
本当に？
Really?
嬉しいな
I'm so happy.
だからこのまなんだよ このまなんだよ 周年っていうことで
That's why you're reading the script! Since it's the 5th anniversary...
大本読んでる からもあの配信だけじゃなく いろんな活動 あの一緒に頑張っていければと思います 今後ともよろしくお願いします
Reading the script! I hope we can work hard together not just on streaming, but in various activities. Thank you for your continued support.
誰のじゃ何？ ありがとうございました！
Whose— What is this? Thank you very much!
何？ 何なの？ まがさん すごくない？これ台本読んでるでしょ
What? What is this? Tanigo-san, isn't that amazing? You're reading a script, right?
野郷からのメッセージでした！ ありがとうございます！ 何あれ？
That was a message from Yagoo! Thank you very much! What was that?
なんか 過去帳 今どきのJKってあんな感じなの？ やっぱり あのすごい 世界一のアイドルともなると あな あんな感じなの？
What was that, like a past record? Are modern high school girls like that? As expected of the world's number 1 idol, are you like that?
すごい血色もヤバかったけど 顔色悪くない？ 大丈夫？ちゃんと寝れてる？ ありがとう！
His complexion looked terrible too. Doesn't he look pale? Are you okay? Are you sleeping properly? Thank you!
やばい ちょっと 笑いすぎで強い歌えるかな？この次もう まだね なんか次もありますから
Oh no, I laughed so much, can I even sing strongly? There's still... wait, there's more next!
改めまして お二人ともありがとうございました！
Once again, thank you very much to both of you!
ありがとう！ありがとうね！ すごい マジでなんか
Thank you! Thank you so much! That was seriously...
ネタみたいなメッセージをいただきました！ ありがとうございました！
We received such joke-like messages! Thank you very much!
改めましてね え 皆様ね え スタッフの皆様も え ホロメンも そして ここにいるみんな え 本当に え ここまでありがとうございます これからも よろしくお願いします！
Once again, everyone, staff members, Hololive members, and everyone here... thank you truly for coming this far. Please keep supporting us!
あ そうだ そう ちょっとだけ告知していい？
Oh, that's right, can I make a quick announcement?
え グッズの方を チェック皆様もうしましたか？ なんとね 8月の8日に発売されたグッズがあります！ じゃあ ちょっと出ますかね こちら ドン！
Have you all checked out the merchandise? There's merchandise that was released on August 8th! Shall we show it? Here it is, boom!
5周年記念フルセット こちらね なんと もう販売されておりますけども
The 5th Anniversary Full Set—it's already on sale!
今も概要欄で買えますので えもしね 今からでも気になった方は 是非チェックしてみてね！ え 何があるかというと ドン！こちら！
You can still buy it via the description box, so if you're interested from now on, please check it out! What's included? Boom! Here it is!
え B2タペストリー かわいいね ふわり先生に描き下ろししていただいた これね あの準備してる私です。あの今から出かけるぞっていう私です。そしてこちら
B2 Tapestry! So cute! Illustrated by Fuwari-sensei. This is me getting ready. Me heading out now. And next...
え 陰キャ証明書 これね めっちゃ売れてるらしい。これなんかね めっちゃ売れてるという情報を入手します。なんでだよ。
Introvert Certification Card! This is apparently selling super well. I got information that this is selling insanely well. Why?!
なんて みんな みんな陰キャ証明書 欲しい？ いやありがとうございます！ そして こちら ドドン！
Why do you all want an introvert ID card so much? Well, thank you! And next, dodon!
あくたんと一緒におでかけリュックサック これね ずっとリュック 私も欲しくて ちょっと あの一緒におでかけしませんか？ 私もちょっとおでかけの時にリュック持ちたいななんて結構かわいいです！ そして こちら デデン！
Aqua-tan Together Outing Backpack! I've wanted a backpack for a long time, so won't you go out with me? I wanted to carry a backpack when going out, and it's quite cute! And next, deden!
もう最初に出たっちゃったね あくたんとおそろいネックレス これね あの制服衣装で あの私がつけてるネックレスと なんだ おそろいのネックレスです！これネックレスにもなるし あのチャームにもなるんで ぜひこちらもチェックしてください！これもなんか売れてるらしいぞ！
It already appeared at the very beginning—Aqua-tan Matching Necklace! This is a matching necklace with the one I wear in my uniform outfit! It can be used as a necklace or a charm, so please check it out! This is also apparently selling well!
そして ドドン！ はい！ これね全部買ったら え サインが付きまーすっていうフルセットです。なので皆様まだ、まだ買ってない方買ってね！時間ねあの期限あるから買ってねよろしくお願いします！
And dodon! Yes! If you buy all of these, it comes with a signature—that's the full set. So everyone, if you haven't bought it yet, please buy it! There's a time limit, so please buy it! Thank you!
はい ということで そして やばい告知がたくさん え そしてなんとなんとですね え この後 21時15分より えメンシップ限定で アコールライブを 行いたいと思います！ アコールです！ はい ちゃんとね あの この ステージでなんと歌うらしい？
Yes, and there are lots of crazy announcements! And guess what, starting at 21:15 tonight, we'll be holding an encore live exclusively for members! An encore! Yes, and apparently I'll be singing right here on this stage!
ということで、ミニライブがありますので、
So, there's going to be a mini live,
よかったらメンバーシップに入ってね。
so if you'd like, please join the membership!
なんかめちゃでもメンバー増えてる気がするんだけど。
I feel like the number of members
なんかめっさでもメンバー増えてる気がするんだけど。
has increased a lot.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ぜひみんなメンバー入ってくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if everyone joined the membership.
おメンゲよろしくね。
Please treat me well!
そしてえー、次が最後の曲となるんですが、
And uh, the next song will be the last one,
ライブで歌うのは初めてのオリジナル曲になっております。こちらです！
this will be the first time singing an original song at a live. Here it is!
でれん！
Ta-da!
君の最推しにしてよ！
Make me your ultimate favorite!
こちらね、なんか誕生日か何かに、実はおあのもうあの配信は開始されてはいたんですが、
Actually, uh, the stream had already started, but
はい、こちらHoneyWorksさんがえっと書き下ろしてくださりまして、「君の最推しにしてよ！」のMVがなんとこの後21時5分よりプレミア公開となります！
HoneyWorks wrote this for me, and the MV will premiere at 5 past 9 PM!
これね、MVなんとですね、HoneyWorksさんがプロデュースして作ってくださいました！すごい！
And the MV was produced and made by HoneyWorks!
なのでぜひね、MVもみに、そして曲を知らない方はぜひ曲を知ってもらうために、ぜひチェックしてもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
So please check out the MV, and for those who don't know the song, to get to know it, I'd be happy if you check it out.
それではこの曲聞いていただきたいと思います。最後の曲です！
Now I'd like you to listen to this song. It's the final song!
君の最推しにしてよ！
Make me your ultimate favorite!
ハートをくれた分だけ 私は君に恋する
As much as you give me hearts, I fall in love with you.
ハートをくれた分だけ 私は夢を叶える
As much as you give me hearts, I make my dreams come true.
ねぇ 愛して？ 愛して？ 一緒に行こう？
Hey, love me? Love me? Shall we go together?
頂上目指す 我が民よ！
My people aiming for the top!
憧れのアイドル目指して
Aiming to be the idol I admire,
配信にレッスン忙しいです
Streams and lessons keep me so busy.
疲れてる時に見てしまった
When I was exhausted, I happened to see
アンチコメントに落ち込む
negative comments and felt so down.
「才能無い」「努力は無駄」「辞めろ」とか
"No talent," "Effort is useless," "Just quit," and such—
呑み込めず飲まれそうな時もある
Sometimes I can't swallow them and get swallowed up instead.
大嫌い 大嫌い 弱虫ハート
I hate it, I hate it, my cowardly heart.
もっと強くなるために君の最推しにしてよ！
To become stronger, make me your ultimate favorite!
ハートをくれた分だけ 私は君に恋する
As much as you give me hearts, I fall in love with you.
くれた分だけ 私は夢を叶える
As much as you give me, I make my dreams come true.
ねぇ 愛して？ 愛して？ 一緒に行こう？
Hey, love me? Love me? Shall we go together?
頂上目指す 我が民よ！
My people aiming for the top!
分かればよろしい！
Good if you understand!
応援してくれてる君に
To you who support me,
ありがとうオムライス
Thank you, omurice!
元気でない時会いに来て
When you're feeling down, come see me,
絶対笑顔にするから！
I'll definitely make you smile!
「実力無い」「トップは無理」「消えろ」とか
"No ability," "Reaching the top is impossible," "Disappear," and such—
呑み込めず飲まれそうな時もある
Sometimes I can't swallow them and get swallowed up instead.
大嫌い 大嫌い ネガティブ私
I hate it, I hate it, my negative self.
もっと強くなるために君の最推しにしてよ！
To become stronger, make me your ultimate favorite!
推し活増えた分だけ 私は君に恋する
As much as my oshi activities increase, I fall in love with you.
増えた分だけ 私は夢中になれる
As much as it increases, I can be absorbed in you.
ねぇ どうしよう？ どうしよう？ 叶えちゃうかも？
Hey, what should I do? What should I do? Might make it come true?
夢を叶えかけちゃうかも 夢を叶え叶え…我が民よ！
Might almost make my dreams come true... My people!
振り返れば最初は泣いてばかりだったけど
Looking back, at first I was always crying, but
もう大丈夫 いつもありがとね
It's already okay, thank you always.
もう大丈夫 君が隣にいてくれる
It's already okay, you're right by my side.
もう大丈夫 君が愛してくれる 君が名前を呼んでくれる
It's already okay, you love me, you call my name.
君の酸素は？ たん！ 君の血肉は？ たん！
Your oxygen? Tan! Your flesh and blood? Tan!
君の女神は？ たん！ 今日の主役は？ たん！
Your goddess? Tan! Today's protagonist? Tan!
「才能無い」「努力は無駄」やめろとか…
"You have no talent," "Your effort is wasted," "Just quit"...
そうかもって飲まれそうな時もある
Sometimes I feel like I might just succumb to those thoughts.
大嫌い 大嫌い 弱虫ハート
I hate it, I hate it, my cowardly heart!
もっともっと強くなるために 君の最推しにしてよ！
To become stronger and stronger, make me your absolute favorite!
ハートをくれた分だけ 私は君に恋する
For every bit of heart you give me, I fall in love with you.
くれた分だけ 私は夢を叶える
For every bit you give me, I make my dreams come true.
愛して 愛して 一緒に行こう
Love me, love me, let's go together!
ちょーちょーめっチャス 我が民よ
Oh, you super, super, incredibly selfish subjects!
わかればよろしい！
Glad you understand!
おしまい！
All done!